

## **Kavita Lodha** klmatri13@gmail.com 91-9819377247

# **Profile Summary**

Experienced HR Professional with 14 years of experience in HR. Handled Lateral Recruitment, Manpower Planning, Compensation, Internal Communication, Branding, Marketing of training programs during my stints in reputed companies like M&M, L&T and Tata's, Internal Audit firm. MBA-HR (MMS-2005), LLB (2009), MCOM (2006) from Mumbai University.

#### **Work Experience**

- **Employee life cycle management:** Responsible for entire employee lifecycle from hire to retire in Aneja Associates.
- Talent Acquisition: Led and handled Talent Acquisition in manufacturing companies like L&T, Tata Rallis and CA firm Aneja Associates. Managed corporate and plant level positions across entry level, mid senior and senior level positions. Hired engineers for chemical and infrastructure projects, CA's, finance professionals, streamlined the process, improved employee referral policy, Onboarding. managed recruitment vendors, anchored background verification. Skilled at using Thomas Profiling and Predictive Index tests during interview process.
- Learning and Development: Training need analysis to understand skill gaps, matching the needs with training programs or designing new programs like Digitization programs in Mahindra and Mahindra.
- Employee Engagement: Instrumental in conducting company-wide engagement survey and action planning. Driving employee engagement events, attrition analysis, taking post joining 30-90-180 days feedback of new joinees and improving the onboarding process. Regular formal and informal connects and meetings with individuals and teams from various departments. Resolving employee grievances promptly.
- **Performance Appraisal:** Anchored PMS process, annual goal setting, mid year review and final appraisal process for employees both manual and in HR software.
- **HRIS Software Data updation:** Used HR softwares like Employee Central, OMS, Keka, etc. Ensured that employee data is always updated in the system.
- **Payroll:** Managed payroll using third party vendor and related statutory compliances like PF, PTax, ESIC etc.
- Compensation: Conducted compensation benchmarking survey through Mercer in Tata Rallis. Designed compensation guidelines for fresh engineers, sales people. Suggested reduction in variable pay for entry level finance professionals.
- Management and Employee relations: Acting as a bridge between management and employees.
- **HR Policies:** Instrumental in revamping HR policies like Travel, Medical Insurance, Death in service, mobile usage etc.

• Developed internal communication content like editing news articles for uploading on group intranet, developed content for quarterly Newsletter and Quality wall, training mailers, ebrochure, managed Linked-in page etc. Instrumental in launching Group-wide Branding Awareness survey for theinstitute to assess perception

## **Employment History**

• Aneja Associates which is a leading Internal audit firm, Mumbai

Head HR & Admin Oct 2022 – Jan 2023

• **Mahindra & Mahindra,** Mumbai as Manager

Nov 2012 - Jun 2019

• TATA Group company Rallis India, Mumbai as Assistant Manager-HR

Which is a leading agrochemical company.

May 2009 - Oct 2012

• Larsen & Toubro Ltd, Mumbai as HR Officer

Oct 2008 - Mar 2009

• Mahindra & Mahindra Ltd, Mumbai as Assistant Manager

Nov 2005 - Oct 2008

## **Trainings attended**

- 1. Centre for Creative Leadership (CCL) Early Leaders Program
- 2. Certified Predictive Index Analyst
- 3. Thomas Profiling
- 4. Competency Based Interviewing techniques Train the Trainers program by British faculty
- 5. Negotiation skills

#### **Skill Set**

Human Resources head, Strategic HR, Recruitment, Training, Negotiation, Leadership, Management, People Leadership, HR Operations, Entrepreneurship.

### **Academic Credentials**

3 years fulltime LLB from New Law College, Mumbai University	2009
MCOM from Mumbai University through distance education	2006
Fulltime MBA (MMS) in Human Resource Management from Alkesh Dinesh	2005
Mody Institute for Financial & Management Studies (Dept of Mumbai University)	
BCOM from D.G. Ruparel college, Mumbai University- Secured 60% marks	2002
HSC from D.G. Ruparel college, Mumbai University- Secured 75% marks	1998
SSC from Sharadashram Vidyamandir, Mumbai University- Secured 87% marks	1996

#### **Personal Details**

Date of Birth : 13<sup>th</sup> June, 1980

Address : Dadar and Borivali East

Marital Status : Single